<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
  <records>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Dai, Yifan
          </author>
          <author>
            You, Lingchong
          </author>
          <author>
            Chilkoti, Ashutosh
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Engineering synthetic biomolecular condensates</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>4</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>1</volume>
      <pages>466-480</pages>
      <issue>7</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s44222-023-00052-6</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Nature Reviews Bioengineering</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Bracha, Dan
          </author>
          <author>
            Walls, Mackenzie T
          </author>
          <author>
            Brangwynne, Clifford P
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Probing and engineering liquid-phase organelles</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2019</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>37</volume>
      <pages>1435-1445</pages>
      <issue>12</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s41587-019-0341-6</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Cells compartmentalize their intracellular environment to orchestrate countless simultaneous biochemical processes. Many intracellular tasks rely on membrane-less organelles, multicomponent condensates that assemble by liquid–liquid phase separation. A decade of intensive research has provided a basic understanding of the biomolecular driving forces underlying the form and function of such organelles. Here we review the technologies enabling these developments, along with approaches to designing spatiotemporally actuated organelles based on multivalent low-affinity interactions. With these recent advances, it is now becoming possible both to modulate the properties of native condensates and to engineer entirely new structures, with the potential for widespread biomedical and biotechnological applications.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Nature Biotechnology</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;doi.org&#x2F;10.1038&#x2F;s41587-019-0341-6</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Kilgore, Henry R
          </author>
          <author>
            Young, Richard A
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Learning the chemical grammar of biomolecular condensates</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>18</volume>
      <pages>1298-1306</pages>
      <issue>12</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s41589-022-01046-y</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Biomolecular condensates compartmentalize and regulate assemblies of biomolecules engaged in vital physiological processes in cells. Specific proteins and nucleic acids engaged in shared functions occur in any one kind of condensate, suggesting that these compartments have distinct chemical specificities. Indeed, some small-molecule drugs concentrate in specific condensates due to chemical properties engendered by particular amino acids in the proteins in those condensates. Here we argue that the chemical properties that govern molecular interactions between a small molecule and biomolecules within a condensate can be ascertained for both the small molecule and the biomolecules. We propose that learning this ‘chemical grammar’, the rules describing the chemical features of small molecules that engender attraction or repulsion by the physicochemical environment of a specific condensate, should enable design of drugs with improved efficacy and reduced toxicity.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Nature Chemical Biology</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;doi.org&#x2F;10.1038&#x2F;s41589-022-01046-y</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Holehouse, Alex S
          </author>
          <author>
            Kragelund, Birthe B
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>The molecular basis for cellular function of intrinsically disordered protein regions</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>25</volume>
      <pages>187-211</pages>
      <issue>3</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s41580-023-00673-0</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Intrinsically disordered protein regions exist in a collection of dynamic interconverting conformations that lack a stable 3D structure. These regions are structurally heterogeneous, ubiquitous and found across all kingdoms of life. Despite the absence of a defined 3D structure, disordered regions are essential for cellular processes ranging from transcriptional control and cell signalling to subcellular organization. Through their conformational malleability and adaptability, disordered regions extend the repertoire of macromolecular interactions and are readily tunable by their structural and chemical context, making them ideal responders to regulatory cues. Recent work has led to major advances in understanding the link between protein sequence and conformational behaviour in disordered regions, yet the link between sequence and molecular function is less well defined. Here we consider the biochemical and biophysical foundations that underlie how and why disordered regions can engage in productive cellular functions, provide examples of emerging concepts and discuss how protein disorder contributes to intracellular information processing and regulation of cellular function.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Nature Reviews Molecular Cell Biology</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;doi.org&#x2F;10.1038&#x2F;s41580-023-00673-0</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Li, Manjia
          </author>
          <author>
            Park, Byung Min
          </author>
          <author>
            Dai, Xin
          </author>
          <author>
            Xu, Yingjie
          </author>
          <author>
            Huang, Jinqing
          </author>
          <author>
            Sun, Fei
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Controlling synthetic membraneless organelles by a red-light-dependent singlet oxygen-generating protein</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>13</volume>
      <pages>3197</pages>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s41467-022-30933-0</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Membraneless organelles (MLOs) formed via protein phase separation have great implications for both physiological and pathological processes. However, the inability to precisely control the bioactivities of MLOs has hindered our understanding of their roles in biology, not to mention their translational applications. Here, by combining intrinsically disordered domains such as RGG and mussel-foot proteins, we create an in cellulo protein phase separation system, of which various biological activities can be introduced via metal-mediated protein immobilization and further controlled by the water-soluble chlorophyll protein (WSCP)—a remarkably stable, red-light-responsive singlet oxygen generator. The WSCP-laden protein condensates undergo a liquid-to-solid phase transition on light exposure, due to oxidative crosslinking, providing a means to control catalysis within synthetic MLOs. Moreover, these photoresponsive condensates, which retain the light-induced phase-transition behavior in living cells, exhibit marked membrane localization, reminiscent of the semi-membrane-bound compartments like postsynaptic densities in nervous systems. Together, this engineered system provides an approach toward controllable synthetic MLOs and, alongside its light-induced phase transition, may well serve to emulate and explore the aging process at the subcellular or even molecular level.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Nature Communications</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;doi.org&#x2F;10.1038&#x2F;s41467-022-30933-0</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Gomes, Edward
          </author>
          <author>
            Shorter, James
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>The molecular language of membraneless organelles</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2019</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>5</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>294</volume>
      <pages>7115-7127</pages>
      <issue>18</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1074&#x2F;jbc.TM118.001192</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Journal of Biological Chemistry</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Boyd-Shiwarski, Cary R.
          </author>
          <author>
            Shiwarski, Daniel J.
          </author>
          <author>
            Griffiths, Shawn E.
          </author>
          <author>
            Beacham, Rebecca T.
          </author>
          <author>
            Norrell, Logan
          </author>
          <author>
            Morrison, Daryl E.
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Jun
          </author>
          <author>
            Mann, Jacob
          </author>
          <author>
            Tennant, William
          </author>
          <author>
            Anderson, Eric N.
          </author>
          <author>
            Franks, Jonathan
          </author>
          <author>
            Calderon, Michael
          </author>
          <author>
            Connolly, Kelly A.
          </author>
          <author>
            Cheema, Muhammad Umar
          </author>
          <author>
            Weaver, Claire J.
          </author>
          <author>
            Nkashama, Lubika J.
          </author>
          <author>
            Weckerly, Claire C.
          </author>
          <author>
            Querry, Katherine E.
          </author>
          <author>
            Pandey, Udai Bhan
          </author>
          <author>
            Donnelly, Christopher J.
          </author>
          <author>
            Sun, Dandan
          </author>
          <author>
            Rodan, Aylin R.
          </author>
          <author>
            Subramanya, Arohan R.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>WNK kinases sense molecular crowding and rescue cell volume via phase separation</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>11</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>185</volume>
      <pages>4488-4506.e20</pages>
      <issue>24</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.cell.2022.09.042</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Cell</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Shi, Yi
          </author>
          <author>
            Liao, Yuan
          </author>
          <author>
            Liu, Qianlong
          </author>
          <author>
            Ni, Zhihao
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Zhenzhen
          </author>
          <author>
            Shi, Minglei
          </author>
          <author>
            Li, Pilong
          </author>
          <author>
            Li, Haitao
          </author>
          <author>
            Rao, Yu
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>BRD4-targeting PROTAC as a unique tool to study biomolecular condensates</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>5</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>9</volume>
      <pages>47</pages>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s41421-023-00544-0</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>&lt;p&gt;Biomolecular condensates play key roles in various biological processes. However, specific condensation modulators are currently lacking. PROTAC is a new technology that can use small molecules to degrade target proteins specifically. PROTAC molecules are expected to regulate biomolecular condensates dynamically by degrading&#x2F;recovering key molecules in biomolecular condensates. In this study, we employed a BRD4-targeting PROTAC molecule to regulate the super-enhancer (SE) condensate and monitored the changes of SE condensate under PROTAC treatment using live-cell imaging and high-throughput sequencing technologies. As a result, we found that BRD4-targeting PROTACs can significantly reduce the BRD4 condensates, and we established a quantitative method for tracking BRD4 condensates by PROTAC and cellular imaging. Surprisingly and encouragingly, BRD4 condensates were observed to preferentially form and play specialized roles in biological process regulation for the first time. Additionally, BRD4 PROTAC makes it possible to observe the dynamics of other condensate components under the continued disruption of BRD4 condensates. Together, these results shed new light on research methods for liquid-liquid phase separation (LLPS), and specifically demonstrate that PROTAC presents a powerful and distinctive tool for the study of biomolecular condensates.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Cell Discovery</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="generic"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Ryan, Veronica H.
          </author>
          <author>
            Fawzi, Nicolas L.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Physiological, Pathological, and Targetable Membraneless Organelles in Neurons</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2019</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>10</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>42</volume>
      <pages>693-708</pages>
      <issue>10</issue>
      <accession-num>31493925</accession-num>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.tins.2019.08.005</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Neurons require unique subcellular compartmentalization to function efficiently. Formed from proteins and RNAs through liquid–liquid phase separation, membraneless organelles (MLOs) have emerged as one way in which cells form distinct, specialized compartments in the absence of lipid membranes. We first discuss MLOs that are common to many cell types as well as those that are specific to neurons. Interestingly, many proteins associated with neurodegenerative disease are found in MLOs, particularly in stress and transport granules. We next review possible links between neurodegeneration and MLOs, and the hypothesis that the protein and RNA inclusions formed in disease are related to the functional complexes occurring inside these MLOs. Finally, we discuss the hypothesis that protein post-translational modifications (PTMs), which can alter phase separation, can modulate MLO formation and provide potential new therapeutic strategies for currently untreatable neurodegenerative diseases.</abstract>
      <publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher>
      <periodical><full-title>Trends in Neurosciences</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>LLPS</keyword>
        <keyword>RNA&#x2F;RNP granule</keyword>
        <keyword>membraneless organelle</keyword>
        <keyword>neurodegeneration</keyword>
        <keyword>post-translational modification</keyword>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Song, Sang-Ho
          </author>
          <author>
            Augustine, George J.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Different mechanisms of synapsin-induced vesicle clustering at inhibitory and excitatory synapses</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>8</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>42</volume>
      <pages>113004</pages>
      <issue>8</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.celrep.2023.113004</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Cell Reports</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Brangwynne, Clifford P.
          </author>
          <author>
            Tompa, Peter
          </author>
          <author>
            Pappu, Rohit V.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Polymer physics of intracellular phase transitions</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2015</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>11</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>11</volume>
      <pages>899-904</pages>
      <issue>11</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;nphys3532</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Intracellular organelles are either membrane-bound vesicles or membrane-less compartments that are made up of proteins and RNA. These organelles play key biological roles, by compartmentalizing the cell to enable spatiotemporal control of biological reactions. Recent studies suggest that membrane-less intracellular compartments are multicomponent viscous liquid droplets that form via phase separation. Proteins that have an intrinsic tendency for being conformationally heterogeneous seem to be the main drivers of liquid-liquid phase separation in the cell. These findings highlight the relevance of classical concepts from the physics of polymeric phase transitions for understanding the assembly of intracellular membrane-less compartments. However, applying these concepts is challenging, given the heteropolymeric nature of protein sequences, the complex intracellular environment, and non-equilibrium features intrinsic to cells. This provides new opportunities for adapting established theories and for the emergence of new physics.</abstract>
      <publisher>Nature Publishing Group</publisher>
      <periodical><full-title>Nature Physics</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Xiang, Siheng
          </author>
          <author>
            Kato, Masato
          </author>
          <author>
            Wu, Leeju C.
          </author>
          <author>
            Lin, Yi
          </author>
          <author>
            Ding, Ming
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Yajie
          </author>
          <author>
            Yu, Yonghao
          </author>
          <author>
            McKnight, Steven L.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>The LC Domain of hnRNPA2 Adopts Similar Conformations in Hydrogel Polymers, Liquid-like Droplets, and Nuclei</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2015</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>11</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>163</volume>
      <pages>829-839</pages>
      <issue>4</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.cell.2015.10.040</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Cell</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Mittag, Tanja
          </author>
          <author>
            Pappu, Rohit V.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>A conceptual framework for understanding phase separation and addressing open questions and challenges</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>6</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>82</volume>
      <pages>2201-2214</pages>
      <issue>12</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.molcel.2022.05.018</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Molecular Cell</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Pyne, Partha
          </author>
          <author>
            Mitra, Rajib Kumar
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Excipients Do Regulate Phase Separation in Lysozyme and Thus Also Its Hydration</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>1</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>13</volume>
      <pages>931-938</pages>
      <issue>3</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1021&#x2F;acs.jpclett.1c03449</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="book_section"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Bekkers, John M.
          </author>
          <author>
            Stevens, Charles F.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Chapter 3 Chapter Two different ways evolution makes neurons larger</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>1990</year>
      </dates>
      <pages>37-45</pages>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;S0079-6123(08)61239-X</electronic-resource-num>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Kim, Goeun
          </author>
          <author>
            Lee, Sang-Eun
          </author>
          <author>
            Jeong, Seonyoung
          </author>
          <author>
            Lee, Jeongkun
          </author>
          <author>
            Park, Daehun
          </author>
          <author>
            Chang, Sunghoe
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Multivalent electrostatic pi–cation interaction between synaptophysin and synapsin is responsible for the coacervation</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2021</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>12</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <pages>137</pages>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1186&#x2F;s13041-021-00846-y</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>&lt;p&gt; We recently showed that synaptophysin (Syph) and synapsin (Syn) can induce liquid–liquid phase separation (LLPS) to cluster small synaptic-like microvesicles in living cells which are highly reminiscent of SV cluster. However, as there is no physical interaction between them, the underlying mechanism for their coacervation remains unknown. Here, we showed that the coacervation between Syph and Syn is primarily governed by multivalent &lt;italic&gt;pi&lt;&#x2F;italic&gt; –cation electrostatic interactions among tyrosine residues of Syph C-terminal (Ct) and positively charged Syn. We found that Syph Ct is intrinsically disordered and it alone can form liquid droplets by interactions among themselves at high concentration in a crowding environment in vitro or when assisted by additional interactions by tagging with light-sensitive CRY2PHR or subunits of a multimeric protein in living cells. Syph Ct contains 10 repeated sequences, 9 of them start with tyrosine, and mutating 9 tyrosine to serine (9YS) completely abolished the phase separating property of Syph Ct, indicating tyrosine-mediated &lt;italic&gt;pi&lt;&#x2F;italic&gt; -interactions are critical. We further found that 9YS mutation failed to coacervate with Syn, and since 9YS retains Syph’s negative charge, the results indicate that &lt;italic&gt;pi&lt;&#x2F;italic&gt; –cation interactions rather than simple charge interactions are responsible for their coacervation. In addition to revealing the underlying mechanism of Syph and Syn coacervation, our results also raise the possibility that physiological regulation of &lt;italic&gt;pi&lt;&#x2F;italic&gt; –cation interactions between Syph and Syn during synaptic activity may contribute to the dynamics of synaptic vesicle clustering. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Molecular Brain</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1CIETW_-xPlDzAjodx7DQao6gCcCaeOFC0w8z0v_Uv5M&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;drive_link</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Kim, Jee Hae
          </author>
          <author>
            Liao, Dezhi
          </author>
          <author>
            Lau, Lit-Fui
          </author>
          <author>
            Huganir, Richard L
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>SynGAP: a Synaptic RasGAP that Associates with the PSD-95&#x2F;SAP90 Protein Family</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>1998</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>4</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>20</volume>
      <pages>683-691</pages>
      <issue>4</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;S0896-6273(00)81008-9</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Neuron</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Araki, Yoichi
          </author>
          <author>
            Rajkovich, Kacey E.
          </author>
          <author>
            Gerber, Elizabeth E.
          </author>
          <author>
            Gamache, Timothy R.
          </author>
          <author>
            Johnson, Richard C.
          </author>
          <author>
            Tran, Thanh Hai N.
          </author>
          <author>
            Liu, Bian
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhu, Qianwen
          </author>
          <author>
            Hong, Ingie
          </author>
          <author>
            Kirkwood, Alfredo
          </author>
          <author>
            Huganir, Richard
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>SynGAP regulates synaptic plasticity and cognition independently of its catalytic activity</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>3</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>383</volume>
      <issue>6686</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1126&#x2F;science.adk1291</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>&lt;p&gt; SynGAP is an abundant synaptic GTPase-activating protein (GAP) critical for synaptic plasticity, learning, memory, and cognition. Mutations in &lt;italic&gt;SYNGAP1&lt;&#x2F;italic&gt; in humans result in intellectual disability, autistic-like behaviors, and epilepsy. Heterozygous &lt;italic&gt;Syngap1&lt;&#x2F;italic&gt; -knockout mice display deficits in synaptic plasticity, learning, and memory and exhibit seizures. It is unclear whether SynGAP imparts structural properties at synapses independently of its GAP activity. Here, we report that inactivating mutations within the GAP domain do not inhibit synaptic plasticity or cause behavioral deficits. Instead, SynGAP modulates synaptic strength by physically competing with the AMPA-receptor-TARP excitatory receptor complex in the formation of molecular condensates with synaptic scaffolding proteins. These results have major implications for developing therapeutic treatments for &lt;italic&gt;SYNGAP1&lt;&#x2F;italic&gt; -related neurodevelopmental disorders. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Science</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Caya-Bissonnette, Léa
          </author>
          <author>
            Béïque, Jean-Claude
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Half a century legacy of long-term potentiation</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>7</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>34</volume>
      <pages>R640-R662</pages>
      <issue>13</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.cub.2024.05.008</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Current Biology</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1jXM9OikpE6F2AdCyBVm0zjJAhBJs4aKvROTp_LKiy0U&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;drive_link</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Yan, Peipei
          </author>
          <author>
            Liu, Huicong
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhou, Tao
          </author>
          <author>
            Sun, Pu
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Yilin
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Xibin
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Lin
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Tian
          </author>
          <author>
            Dong, Jing
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhu, Jiangli
          </author>
          <author>
            Lv, Luxian
          </author>
          <author>
            Li, Wenqiang
          </author>
          <author>
            Qi, Shiqian
          </author>
          <author>
            Liang, Yinming
          </author>
          <author>
            Kong, Eryan
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Crosstalk of Synapsin1 palmitoylation and phosphorylation controls the dynamicity of synaptic vesicles in neurons</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>9</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>13</volume>
      <pages>786</pages>
      <issue>9</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s41419-022-05235-4</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>&lt;p&gt;The dynamics of synaptic vesicles (SVs) within presynaptic domains are tightly controlled by synapsin1 phosphorylation; however, the mechanism underlying the anchoring of synapsin1 with F-actin or SVs is not yet fully understood. Here, we found that Syn1 is modified with protein palmitoylation, and examining the roles of Syn1 palmitoylation in neurons led us to uncover that Syn1 palmitoylation is negatively regulated by its phosphorylation; together, they manipulate the clustering and redistribution of SVs. Using the combined approaches of electron microscopy and genetics, we revealed that Syn1 palmitoylation is vital for its binding with F-actin but not SVs. Inhibition of Syn1 palmitoylation causes defects in SVs clustering and a reduced number of total SVs in vivo. We propose a model in which SVs redistribution is triggered by upregulated Syn1 phosphorylation and downregulated Syn1 palmitoylation, and they reversibly promote SVs clustering. The crosstalk of Syn1 palmitoylation and phosphorylation thereby bidirectionally manipulates SVs dynamics in neurons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Cell Death &amp; Disease</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1pbuOWLJPcxUHDLM24uPRqlRPTi_Goc842G7gxmxg4D0&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Christensen, Nikolaj Riis
          </author>
          <author>
            Pedersen, Christian Parsbæk
          </author>
          <author>
            Sereikaite, Vita
          </author>
          <author>
            Pedersen, Jannik Nedergaard
          </author>
          <author>
            Vistrup-Parry, Maria
          </author>
          <author>
            Sørensen, Andreas Toft
          </author>
          <author>
            Otzen, Daniel
          </author>
          <author>
            Teilum, Kaare
          </author>
          <author>
            Madsen, Kenneth Lindegaard
          </author>
          <author>
            Strømgaard, Kristian
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Bidirectional protein–protein interactions control liquid–liquid phase separation of PSD-95 and its interaction partners</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>2</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>25</volume>
      <pages>103808</pages>
      <issue>2</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.isci.2022.103808</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>iScience</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;18oaG1V8VH_lLKe3Y6m_8Fg0vkU4Ki22R8ovI5ZtjlDM&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;drive_link</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Xiang, Li
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Jiawen
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Wenda
          </author>
          <author>
            Gong, Lu
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Ling
          </author>
          <author>
            Yan, Bin
          </author>
          <author>
            Zeng, Hongbo
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Nanomechanics of π-cation-π interaction with implications for bio-inspired wet adhesion</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2020</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>11</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>117</volume>
      <pages>294-301</pages>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.actbio.2020.09.043</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Acta Biomaterialia</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1RGgOpcs15b7r6tk1zq3E_GP0-OAsZHssO-X4XN1A8is&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Fan, Hailong
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Jiahui
          </author>
          <author>
            Tao, Zhen
          </author>
          <author>
            Huang, Junchao
          </author>
          <author>
            Rao, Ping
          </author>
          <author>
            Kurokawa, Takayuki
          </author>
          <author>
            Gong, Jian Ping
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Adjacent cationic–aromatic sequences yield strong electrostatic adhesion of hydrogels in seawater</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2019</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>11</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>10</volume>
      <pages>5127</pages>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s41467-019-13171-9</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>&lt;p&gt;Electrostatic interaction is strong but usually diminishes in high ionic-strength environments. Biosystems can use this interaction through adjacent cationic–aromatic amino acids sequence of proteins even in a saline medium. Application of such specific sequence to the development of cationic polymer materials adhesive to negatively charged surfaces in saline environments is challenging due to the difficulty in controlling the copolymer sequences. Here, we discover that copolymers with adjacent cation–aromatic sequences can be synthesized through cation–π complex-aided free-radical polymerization. Sequence controlled hydrogels from diverse cation&#x2F;aromatic monomers exhibit fast, strong but reversible adhesion to negatively charged surfaces in seawater. Aromatics on copolymers are found to enhance the electrostatic interactions of their adjacent cationic residues to the counter surfaces, even in a high ionic-strength medium that screens the electrostatic interaction for common polyelectrolytes. This work opens a pathway to develop adhesives using saline water.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Nature Communications</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1NCTHyJ3_5sm2Z_1048OH4SMlYrZ0Qsl-1JgTO04Lchs&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Fan, Hailong
          </author>
          <author>
            Guo, Honglei
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Jiahui
          </author>
          <author>
            Gong, Jian Ping
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Competitive cation−π interactions between small cations and polycations with phenyl groups in poly(cation−π) hydrogels</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2020</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>3</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>1</volume>
      <pages>100005</pages>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.giant.2020.100005</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Giant</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1hUi0JSLn6WMKPqLAsJtdfVdGg9PTxCLpwRW2V9vwgPc&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Arias, Sandra
          </author>
          <author>
            Freire, Félix
          </author>
          <author>
            Quiñoá, Emilio
          </author>
          <author>
            Riguera, Ricardo
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>The leading role of cation–π interactions in polymer chemistry: the control of the helical sense in solution</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2015</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>6</volume>
      <pages>4725-4733</pages>
      <issue>26</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1039&#x2F;C5PY00587F</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>&lt;p&gt; Cation–π interactions determine the helical sense adopted by a polyphenylacetylene bearing ( &lt;italic&gt;R&lt;&#x2F;italic&gt; )-α-methoxy-α-phenylacetamide as a pendant group (poly- &lt;bold&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;bold&gt; ). &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Polymer Chemistry</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1jDwLO0pZYMUf66NampJNIuYKt30WwnTbUPcz7F6eoak&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;drive_link</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Klink, B. U.
          </author>
          <author>
            Alavizargar, A.
          </author>
          <author>
            Kalyankumar, K. S.
          </author>
          <author>
            Chen, M.
          </author>
          <author>
            Heuer, A.
          </author>
          <author>
            Gatsogiannis, C.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Structural basis of α-latrotoxin transition to a cation-selective pore</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>10</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>15</volume>
      <pages>8551</pages>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1038&#x2F;s41467-024-52635-5</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>&lt;p&gt; The potent neurotoxic venom of the black widow spider contains a cocktail of seven phylum-specific latrotoxins (LTXs), but only one, α-LTX, targets vertebrates. This 130 kDa toxin binds to receptors at presynaptic nerve terminals and triggers a massive release of neurotransmitters. It is widely accepted that LTXs tetramerize and insert into the presynaptic membrane, thereby forming Ca &lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; -conductive pores, but the underlying mechanism remains poorly understood. LTXs are homologous and consist of an N-terminal region with three distinct domains, along with a C-terminal domain containing up to 22 consecutive ankyrin repeats. Here we report cryoEM structures of the vertebrate-specific α-LTX tetramer in its prepore and pore state. Our structures, in combination with AlphaFold2-based structural modeling and molecular dynamics simulations, reveal dramatic conformational changes in the N-terminal region of the complex. Four distinct helical bundles rearrange and together form a highly stable, 15 nm long, cation-impermeable coiled-coil stalk. This stalk, in turn, positions an N-terminal pair of helices within the membrane, thereby enabling the assembly of a cation-permeable channel. Taken together, these data give insight into a unique mechanism for membrane insertion and channel formation, characteristic of the LTX family, and provide the necessary framework for advancing novel therapeutics and biotechnological applications. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Nature Communications</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1paxfR31gk_qX9vZZP16tBvMAubyyl7ZsDaDtWbQU6Z8&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Denker, Annette
          </author>
          <author>
            Kröhnert, Katharina
          </author>
          <author>
            Bückers, Johanna
          </author>
          <author>
            Neher, Erwin
          </author>
          <author>
            Rizzoli, Silvio O.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>The reserve pool of synaptic vesicles acts as a buffer for proteins involved in synaptic vesicle recycling</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2011</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>10</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>108</volume>
      <pages>17183-17188</pages>
      <issue>41</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1073&#x2F;pnas.1112690108</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>&lt;p&gt;Presynaptic nerve terminals contain between several hundred vesicles (for example in small CNS synapses) and several tens of thousands (as in neuromuscular junctions). Although it has long been assumed that such high numbers of vesicles are required to sustain neurotransmission during conditions of high demand, we found that activity in vivo requires the recycling of only a few percent of the vesicles. However, the maintenance of large amounts of reserve vesicles in many evolutionarily distinct species suggests that they are relevant for synaptic function. We suggest here that these vesicles constitute buffers for soluble accessory proteins involved in vesicle recycling, preventing their loss into the axon. Supporting this hypothesis, we found that vesicle clusters contain a large variety of proteins needed for vesicle recycling, but without an obvious function within the clusters. Disrupting the clusters by application of black widow spider venom resulted in the diffusion of numerous soluble proteins into the axons. Prolonged stimulation and ionomycin application had a similar effect, suggesting that calcium influx causes the unbinding of soluble proteins from vesicles. Confirming this hypothesis, we found that isolated synaptic vesicles in vitro sequestered soluble proteins from the cytosol in a process that was inhibited by calcium addition. We conclude that the reserve vesicles support neurotransmission indirectly, ensuring that soluble recycling proteins are delivered upon demand during synaptic activity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;13gioootICR3MgteFQjk_dKFKeO3p6JXrMPB9t76c5Nk&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Dinadayalane, Tandabany C.
          </author>
          <author>
            Hassan, Ayorinde
          </author>
          <author>
            Leszczynski, Jerzy
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>A theoretical study of cation--π interactions: Li+, Na+, K+, Be2+, Mg2+ and Ca2+ complexation with mono- and bicyclic ring-fused benzene derivatives</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2012</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>3</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>131</volume>
      <pages>1131</pages>
      <issue>3</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1007&#x2F;s00214-012-1131-0</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Theoretical Chemistry Accounts</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1JEKNCo3ZJ4UOdynFWKU8Ou6jNSjWp2O0jUy0E21ayAk&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Dougherty, Dennis A.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>The Cation−π Interaction</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2013</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>4</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>46</volume>
      <pages>885-893</pages>
      <issue>4</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1021&#x2F;ar300265y</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>Accounts of Chemical Research</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1uxpg3cDKT7GKj8EqPyg98i0Tf-PMEzCOl3yPsjeqZyA&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Hazra, Milan Kumar
          </author>
          <author>
            Levy, Yaakov
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Cross-Talk of Cation−π Interactions with Electrostatic and Aromatic Interactions: A Salt-Dependent Trade-off in Biomolecular Condensates</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>9</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <pages>8460-8469</pages>
      <issue>38</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1021&#x2F;acs.jpclett.3c01642</electronic-resource-num>
      <periodical><full-title>The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.google.com&#x2F;document&#x2F;d&#x2F;1lGvvKb1o_lHriMG1-_yOgFuX6x4SMCHnC5qk_waXFG4&#x2F;edit?usp&#x3D;sharing</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
  </records>
</xml>